RYAN CLARK

Front-end software engineer +44 (0) 7751 061 843

Email: ryan@ryanclark.me Twitter: @rynclark LinkedIn: http://uk.linkedin.com/in/rynclark

Highly experienced front-end software engineer with a wealth of experience in developing applications for blue chip organisations. Confident and outgoing with a passion for emerging standards and performance.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Over 5 years personal and 3 years commercial experience combining the following technologies:

- JavaScript
 - ECMAScript 5
 - o ECMAScript 6
- HTML5
 - o APIs
 - Semantics
- Frameworks/libraries
 - o AngularJS
 - React.is / JSX
 - iQuery
- Client-side MVC/MVVM
- JSON/JSONP
- Ajax/REST
- Dependency management
 - o Bower
 - o NPM
- Modular JavaScript
 - o AMD
 - CommonJS
 - Browserify
- TDD/BDD
 - o Karma
 - Jasmine
 - o PhantomJS

Tooling

- o Grunt.js
- o Gulp.js
- Traceur compiler
- o JSHint/JSLint
- Node.js
- PHP
- Google Cloud
 - Google Apps Script
 - Google APIs
- Agile/Scrum
- Continuous Integration (CI)
- Performance
 - Chrome dev tools timeline
 - Stack trace analysis/bottlenecking
 - CPU profiling and audits
 - Network monitoring/throttling
 - Responsive media queries
- CSS3

WORK EXPERIENCE

Front-End Engineer: Appsbroker (May 2014 - Now)

- Front-end engineer at the UK's leading Google Enterprise Partner and EMEA Google Partner of the Year 2012. Responsible for the mentoring and development of several other front-end engineers, leading new software projects, internal product development
 - o AngularJS, ReactJS and JavaScript applications
 - o Google APIs, from Maps to Drive

Freelance/Contract Engineer: Smash Six (January 2013 – April 2014)

• Part of the software engineering team to create Javascript applications for corporate clients based in Central London. Utilised frameworks such as AngularJS and jQuery to create rich Ajax-driven web applications

Software Engineer: Team West Ltd (September 2011 – December 2012)

- Franchisee of Domino's Pizza, creating products to use within the Domino's stores
- Created a driver tracking system using the Google Maps API to track drivers in real time, including traffic warnings and routing
- Utilized biometric systems to create an employee portal with fingerprint authentication
 - Used to log time for payroll, provide real time statistics for the stores, and act as a reporting system for the sales

EDUCATION

• GCSEs: A, A, A, B, B, B, B, C, C

RECOGNITION AND ACHIEVEMENTS

- Internal company workshops
- Internal company presentations/training colleagues
- Open source evangelist/contributor